Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
Framed items from the collections of The Bancroft Library
Various
310 items (framed); various 362 digital objects
The Bancroft Library University of California, Berkeley Berkeley, CA 94720-6000 Phone: (510) 642-6481 Fax: (510) 642-7589 Email: bancref@library.berkeley.edu
310 framed items from the collections of The Bancroft Library. Includes paintings, drawings, prints and photographs dating from the late 1600s to the mid-1970s. Subject matter is chiefly California scenes, events, towns and landmarks, as well as numerous portraits of prominent Californians.
Information for Researchers
Access
Restricted originals. Use digital facsimiles or selected viewing prints only. Use of originals only by permission of the Curator of Pictorial Collections, The Bancroft Library.
Digital Representations Available
Digital representations of all original pictorial materials are available as a part of the Container list of the finding aid. Digital image files were captured from originals by the Library Photographic Service. Most Library originals were captured directly using a Phase One Powerphase digital camera back and a Hasselblad camera. Lower-resolution viewing files were prepared from the high-resolution master TIFF files: the master files were downsampled, sharpened, color-corrected, adjusted for a gamma 2.2 viewing environment, and saved in JFIF (JPEG) format before being placed on the server.
Administrative Information
Items from various sources, including gifts to the library and library purchases.
Container Listing
- Individual Framed Items
  - County Fair :The Final Grooming at the Stock Show, [194-?]; Cross, Vina; BANC PIC 1905.17141:120--FR; 1 painting on academy board: oil; 56 x 92 cm. Painted signature (LR): V Cross. Title printed on label (verso). Secondary title handwritten (verso UR). Date of work from biographical and exhibit information handwritten on verso. Extensive biography and provenance information handwritten on verso.
    Content/Description
    View of livestock pens with cows being groomed and washed. Covered arenas with spectators in stands visible in background.
    Oil paintings
  - Mountain home [Mount Saint Helena, Calif.], 1874; Williams, Virgil; BANC PIC 1917.002--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 65.6 x 105.7 cm. Painted title, signature, and date (LR): Mountain Home / Williams 1874 California.
    Rustic dwelling with chickens and coop in the yard set in hilly landscape with numerous oak and pine trees. A small outbuilding is visible in the trees beyond and the foothills and peak of Mt. Saint Helena rises in the distance. Mountain Home Ranch Road still exists in Calistoga, CA.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Saint Helena, Mount (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - St. Antonio de Padua, 1900; Peters, Charles Rollo; BANC PIC 1919.002--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 131.6 x 91 cm. Painted signature, title, and date (LL): Charles Rollo Peters / St. Antonio de Padua, 1900.
    Nocturnal view of western façade of mission building.
    Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; San Antonio de Padua (Mission) -- Pictorial works
  - [T.J. Cobden-Sanderson], 1893; Legros, A.; BANC PIC 1941.008--FR; 1 print: etching(?); image 13 x 8.9 cm on mount (sight) 21.6 x 13.5 cm. Printed signature and date (UR): A[lphonse?] Legros / 1893. Handwritten (LC on mount): T.J. Cobden-Sanderson / to John Henry Nash / -26 June 1921.
    Bust length portrait of writer and book arts craftsman Thomas James Cobden-Sanderson (1840-1922).
    Portraits; Cobden-Sanderson, T. J. -- (Thomas James), -- 1840-1922 -- Portraits
  - [Sitting Bull], 1909; Gray, Percy; BANC PIC 1942.009--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; 41.2 x 25.6 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LL): Percy Gray / 1909.
    Bust length, three-quarter profile portrait of Sioux Indian medicine chief.
    Portraits; Watercolors; Indians of North America -- Plains (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Sitting Bull, -- 1834?-1890 -- Portraits
  - [Portrait of George Davidson], 1886; Keith, William; BANC PIC 1946.003--FR; 1 painting on linen: oil; visible image 59.5 x 49.8 cm. Painted signature and date (UR): W. Keith/1886. Plaque on frame (LC): George Davidson.
    Bust portrait in three-quarter profile of one-time regent of the University of California.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Davidson, George, -- 1825-1911 -- Portraits
  - How I Got That Way, 1953; Goldberg, Reuben L. (Rube); BANC PIC 1953.002:01-04--FR; 3 drawings and 1 page text (matted and framed together): pen, ink, and crayon; 32 x 30 cm. or smaller. Item (1): 28 x 21.4 cm.; Item (2): visible image 12 x 43.9 cm.; Item (3): visible image 13.9 x 43.9 cm.; Item (4): visible image 31.3 x 29.6 cm. Item (1): signature and date (LR): Rube Goldberg / May 1953; Item (2): signature (LR): Rube Goldberg 11-8; Item (3): signature (LR): R. Goldberg; Item (4): signature (LR): Rube Goldberg.
    Item (1): letter entitled "How I Got That Way" relates Goldberg's years as a mining engineering student at U.C. Berkeley to his start as a cartoonist. Item (2): cartoon with a radio announcer and football team. Item (3): cartoon of Professor Butts and self-opening umbrella. Item (4): Abe Lincoln.
    Cartoons (Commentary); Drawings; Goldberg, Rube, -- 1883-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons; Lincoln, Abraham, -- 1809-1865 -- Caricatures and cartoons
  - Bay of Monterey, Upper California, 1827; Smyth, William; BANC PIC 1953.003--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 22.8 x 35.6 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LL): W. Smyth / 1827. Handwritten title (LR).
    Landscape with couple in foreground, buildings left and center, and masted ships in the bay at right, one of which is purported to be the H.M.S. Blossom on which Smyth served under Captain Frederick William Beechy. Smyth often sketched with fellow officer Richard Beechey during their voyage to the Pacific 1825-1828.
    Watercolors; Cities and towns; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Monterey; Blossom (ship) -- Pictorial works; Voyages to the Pacific coast -- Pictorial works; Monterey (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - The Presidio and Pueblo of Monterey, Upper California, 1827; Smyth, William; BANC PIC 1953.004--FR; 1 painting: watercolor on paper; visible image 20.3 x 31.6 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): W. Smyth / 1827. Handwritten title (LR): The Presidio and Pueblo of Monterrey [sic], Upper California.
    Landscape with three men in the foreground; buildings of the Presido and Pueblo at center. Painted during a voyage to the Pacific (1825-1828) on the H.M.S. Blossom under Captain Frederick William Beechy.
    Watercolors; Blossom (ship) -- Pictorial works; Voyages to the Pacific coast -- Pictorial works; Monterey (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Landscapes; Presidio of Monterey (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Hiram W. Johnson, [ca. 1910-1924]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1956.007--FR; 1 photograph: highlighted with white; visible image 72.7 x 54.8 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Hiram W. Johnson.
    Bust portrait of Hiram Johnson (1866-1945).
    Portraits
  - [George Robins], [186-?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1959.093--FR; 1 painting: oil; oval image 68.5 x 55.8 cm. Handwritten title (stretcher, UC). Stamp (on stretcher) from Jones & Woolls picture store, 48 Market St.
    Bust portrait of man (Robins, George W., 1821-1908). Robins, a California pioneer, left New York in March 1849 aboard the bark Clarissa, sailed around Cape Horn and arrived in San Francisco in October of that year. Robins was referred to as a capitalist and a letter apparently written by him to Benjamin S. Hill in 1850 discusses the state of money market in San Francisco at the time.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Robins, George W., -- 1821-1908 -- Portraits
  - Mission Dolores, Looking Towards San Francisco, Oct. 22, 1850; Dougal, William H.; BANC PIC 1960.018:016b--A; 1 drawing: pencil heightened with white; 18 x 26.5 cm. Handwritten title (LC): Mission Dolores, looking towards San Francisco. Handwritten date (LR): Oct. 22nd 1850.
    View from hill, later called Liberty Hill, looking north east across Mission Dolores to San Francisco. In the middle distance is the mission quadrangle, and the fenced line of what would become Dolores Street. At the far right of the drawing is Mission Bay. In the center distance is San Francisco harbor and Yerba Buena Island.
    Two items in the Dougal collection were assigned number 16 by the library. One (16a) is of the front of Mission Dolores. The other (16b, view over Mission Dolores towards San Francisco) was drawn the same day, and was formerly framed. These are reproduced as plates 23 and 24 of "Off for California; the letters, log and sketches of William H. Dougal, gold rush artist", edited by Frank M. Stanger (1949).
    Drawings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Francois Emile Matthes], [ca. 1900-ca. 1948]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1961.005:115--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 59.6 x 49.6 cm.
    Bust-length portrait of Matthes, noted geologist.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Matthes, Fran/lc\cois, -- 1874-1948 -- Portraits
  - [Don Francisco de Lara y Fresnedo], [1674]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1961.022--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 105 x 82.6 cm. Painted (on scroll in image): El Illmo Sor Dn Franco / de Lara y Fresnedo...electo arpo de zaragoza ano de 1674. oil on canvas
    Half-length standing portrait of churchman wearing a scarlet cloak and skull cap with a large cross around his neck. His is flanked by a coat of arms and books behind a drapery swag.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Lara y Fresnedo, Francisco de -- Portraits
  - California fruit, 1855; W.W. Elliott Lithographers; BANC PIC 1962.003:01--C; 1 print: lithograph; sheet 61 x 48 cm. Printed title (LC in image). Printed (LC below title, in image): Painted for the State Agriculture Exhibition, from specimens raised at Smiths Gardens near Sacramento. By Thos. M. Logan, M.D. 1855; Lithographed & printed in colors by Endicott & Co. New York; (on scroll in image): Crawford's late peach, circumference 12 inches, weight near 12 ounces. Smith's California seedling strawberries, longest diameter 2 and 2/10 inches, shortest do 1, 1/4 do. Grapes Black Hamburg average diameter 8/10 inches. Cannon Hall muscat average diameter 9/10 inches. Correct, James L.L.F. Warren Cor. Sec., Cal. St. Ag. Soc.
    Still life of grapes, strawberries and peach with glass dish.
    Lithographs -- Color; Still lifes
  - [Charles Martin Weber], [188-?]; Innes Felder, J.; BANC PIC 1962.003:09--FR; 1 drawing on paper mounted on canvas: charcoal and white chalk; visible oval image 63 x 49.7 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): J. Innes Felder.
    Bust length portrait after a photo by J. Pitcher Spooner.
    Portraits; Charcoal drawings; Weber, Charles David Maria, -- 1814-1881 -- Pictorial works
  - [Don Silvestre Terrazas], [1921?]; Aviola (?), M. Hernandez; BANC PIC 1962.011--FR; 1 painting on canvas; oil; visible image 49 x 39 cm. Painted signature (LR): M. [Hernandez?] Aviola / [?] / [1921?] Engraved plaque (verso) includes sitter's dates and occupation. Handwritten inscription (verso) includes sitter's dates, occupation, and parents and descendants names [signed by Margarita Terrazas]. On stretcher (UL): Fine Arts shop 1-15-21.
    Bust-length portrait of Terrazas, a prominent and politically active journalist born in Chihuahua and educated in Mexico. He was editor of El Correo de Chihuahua and a member of the Prensa Asociada de los Estados, among other activities.
    donor files indicate gift of Margarita Terrazas in 1962.
  - Across the Continent: "Westward the course of empire takes its way", c1868; Ives J.M.; Currier & Ives; Palmer, F. (Fanny); BANC PIC 1963.002:1530--D; 1 print: lithograph, hand colored; 60.4 x 81.8 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): J.M. Ives, Del.; (LC) Entered according to act of Congress in the year AD 1868 by Currier & Ives...; (LR): Drawn by F.F. Palmer; (LC below title): New York Pub. by Currier & Ives. 125 Nassau Street.
    Rail line through small town of log buildings with train in center (Through Line New York - San Francisco). Scene includes men at work in woods; women and children near a public school, church and other buildings; covered wagons being pulled by oxen; a wagon train on trail in distance; and Indians on horses to right.
    Cities and towns; Lithographs -- Hand-colored; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Railroads -- United States -- Pictorial works
  - Switchman's Union of North America Charter, January 19, 1913; Switchman's Union; BANC PIC 1963.033--FR; 1 broadside on paper: b&w and color; visible image 48 x 30.3 cm. Various signatures of Charter members. Document dated (LC): Jan. 19, 1913.
    Includes a small vignette of a train and workmen, the text of the charter, signatures and a seal.
    Broadsides; Switchmen's Union of North America -- Pictorial works; Trade Unions -- Railroads -- United States -- Pacific Coast -- Pictorial works
  - The White House, Canyon de Chelly, 1915; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1964.005--FR; 1 painting: oil; 25.3 x 45.8 cm. Handwritten (verso stretcher UL): The White House / Canyon Del Shelly; (UC): San Diego Exposition 1915.
    Distant view of pueblo ruins.
    Oil paintings; Indians of North America -- Dwellings -- Arizona -- Chelly, Canyon de -- Pictorial works; Canyon de Chelly National Monument (Ariz.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Mount Shasta viewed through trees], [186-?]; Brodt, Helen Tanner; BANC PIC 1965.005--FR; 1 drawing on paper mounted on canvas: pastel; visible image 53.8 x 43.6 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Helen Brodt. Handwritten title (verso): Mt. Shasta.
    Vertical view of Mount Shasta looking through tree-lined slope in the foreground.
    Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Pastels (Visual works); Mount Shasta (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Mount Shasta and a mountain lake], [1865?]; Brodt, Helen Tanner; BANC PIC 1965.006--FR; 1 drawing: pastel; visible image 28 x 38.2 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Helen / Brodt.
    Horizontal view looking through trees towards Mount Shasta with a small lake in foreground.
  - [George P. Hammond: Director of the Bancroft Library, 1946-1965], Stewart, M.D.; BANC PIC 1965.007--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 75 x 54.7 cm. Painted signature (LR): M. D. Stewart 65.
    Half-length seated portrait.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Hammond, George Peter, -- 1896- -- Portraits; Bancroft Library. -- Director -- Portraits
  - [Self portrait of Gerald Cassidy], 1924; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1966.008--FR; 1 painting on canvas: oil; 51 x 40.6 cm. Painted signature (LR): Gerald [sun symbol] Cassidy. Label (on verso, dated August 3, 1958): sold to / Robert E. McKee, / P.O. Drawer 562, / El Paso, Texas. / (signed): Mrs. Gerald Cassidy. Handwritten on stretcher (top): 1924 Gerald Cassidy self-portrait / 1924.
    Bust-length portrait of the artist.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Cassidy, Gerald, -- 1879-1934 -- Portraits; Self-Portraits
  - Bird's-eye view of Redwood City, Cal[ifornia]., 1891; Moore, E.S.; BANC PIC 1968.021--D; 1 lithograph: b&w; sheet 55 x 65.5 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LR in image): E.S. Moore, artist. Printed key to locations in central image (LR and LL).
    View of city with vignettes of Price's Hotel, Wise Planing and Jobbing Mill, Summit Springs Health and Pleasure Resort, Wahl Building and C.J. Hynding residence along the top border; and, in the center bottom, Redwood City House.
    Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; Redwood City (Calif.) -- Aerial views -- Pictorial works; Redwood City (Calif.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works
  - [A mountain scene], [ca. 1890]; Holdridge, R.G. (Ransom Gillett); BANC PIC 1969.005--FR; 1 painting: oil; 39.5 x 50 cm. On stretcher (LL): 71.1.2.
    View of ravine with valley and high mountains in distance. Peasant woman with basket walking through opening in fence in foreground.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes; Mountains -- Pictorial works
  - [Tourist party viewing Yosemite], [ca. 1890]; Schafer, F.F.; BANC PIC 1969.006--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on masonite: oil; visible image 34.6 x 64.8 cm. Handwritten (verso): Herman / Reichel. Label from Oakland Art Museum (Municipal Auditorium Oakland; No. TL 58.35.5).
    Group seated in open wagon drawn by four horses looking at of view of Yosemite Valley from the Mariposa Trail with El Capitan visible in center and Half Dome in the distance.
    Oil paintings; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Yosemite Valley (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Sightseers -- California, Northern; Leisure -- California -- Pictorial works
  - [Untitled river scene: possibly the Columbia River], [ca. 1900]; Schafer, Frederick F. (attr.); BANC PIC 1969.007--FR; 1 painting: oil; 41 x 60.5 cm. Handwritten (R edge): Columbia River? Mt. Hood Cape Horn [modern hand].
    View looking across [Columbia?] river with high peak at left and mountain in distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes; Columbia River -- Pictorial works
  - Fort Point from Baker Beach, [ca. 1880]; Valencia, Manuel; BANC PIC 1969.013--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 76 x 126.3 cm. Painted signature LR: M. Valencia. Title from label (verso).
    View from Baker Beach looking northeast with Fort Point in right distance and Marin headlands in left distance. Steamboat and masted ship at bay.
    Oil paintings; Fort Point (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- San Francisco; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Primitive painting of a man fishing in a mountain lake], [between 1880 and 1900]; Unknown Primitive; BANC PIC 1969.015--FR; 1 painting: oil; 58.3 x 76.5 cm.
    Man fishing from a boat in lake near mountains and a cabin.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes
  - [Horse's head], 1887; Norris, Frank; BANC PIC 1969.020:01--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on board: oil; 20 x 20 cm. Signed (LR): B F Norris 87.
    Bust of horse in agitated state, foaming at the mouth.
    Gift of Dr. Frank Norris, 1969.
    Painted by author Frank Norris (Benjamin Franklin Norris).
  - [Mount Shasta and Shastina Lake], [not before 1857]; Butman, Frederick A.; BANC PIC 1970.003--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 65.3 x 106.7 cm. (verso): S.&G. Gump / importers of / looking glasses, picture frames, mouldings, pictures / no. 117 & 119 Sansome St. S.F. / - Cal. -
    Distant view of snow-capped mountains with small lake in foreground surrounded by an open plain.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Mount Shasta (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Shastina, Lake (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Almond Blossoms and Wild Mustard, Saratoga, California, ca. 1930's; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1970.007--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 75.4 x 90.3 cm. Painted signature (LR): Theodore Wores. Title from label on verso.
    Field with flowering trees and plants and a small wooden building.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Saratoga; Saratoga (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Mount Tamalpais from Corte Madera Creek, 1915; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1970.008--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 39.5 x 49.6 cm. Signature (LR): Theodore Wores. Title and date from label on verso. UC label (verso, LL): 70-10-06912.
    California landscape with wildflowers and oaks in foreground, creek in center, and Mt. Tamalpais in the distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Corte Madera; Corte Madera (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Tamalpais, Mount (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [The Golden Gate from Ocean Cliff, San Francisco], [ca. 1912]; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1970.009--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 39.7 x 49.8 cm. Signature (LL): Theodore Wores.
    Oceanside path along cliff with wild flowers. Buoy visible at left.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- San Francisco; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Golden Gate (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Yosemite Falls], [1930?]; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1970.010--FR; 1 painting on canvas on board: oil (acrylic?); visible image 39.6 x 29.2 cm. Painted signature (LR): Theodore Wores.
    View of upper and lower Yosemite Falls from across meadow.
    Watercolors; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Yosemite National Park; Wilderness areas -- California; Waterfalls -- California -- Yosemite National Park
  - [View of San Francisco waterfront, 1850], [ca. 1870]; Jones, William H.; BANC PIC 1970.011--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 30.9 x 81.2 cm. Painted signature (LR): William H. Jones.
    Based on: Henry Firks' San Francisco: 1849. Drawn on the spot by Henry Firks for [auctioneer] W.H. Jones, Esq. of San Francisco, looking from Market Street sand dunes towards Telegraph Hill.
    Early view of San Francisco showing scattered buildings on waterfront with ships in harbor; one ship is ablaze.
    Oil paintings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Waterfronts -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; Telegraph Hill (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [The Cliff House and Seal Rocks, San Francisco], [ca. 1875]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1970.012--FR; 1 reverse painting on glass: mixed media; visible image 19.2 x 24.5 cm.
    View of Cliff house and beyond from Sutro Heights.
    Oil paintings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Seal Rocks (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Cliff House (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [The miner's dream], [ca. 1860]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1970.038--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 44 x 34 cm.
    View of Australian gold miner seated at a desk asleep, dreaming of a winter homecoming with family, after having read a letter that has fallen to the floor. Set in a rustic cabin, several books lay on the desk while a dog and dead bird lay at his feet.
    Oil paintings; Cabins; Dreams -- Pictorial works; Gold miners -- Australia -- Pictorial works; Miners -- Australia -- Pictorial works
  - [Portrait of Earl Warren, Chief Justice of the United States], [between 1950 and 1960]; Ray, Joan; BANC PIC 1970.045--FR; 1 photograph; 47.3 x 40.1 cm. Handwritten (LL on mat): To: Oscar Jahnsen / my friend and associate / for over 30 years. / [signed] Earl Warren / Chief Justice of the United States. Printed signature (in neg?) (LL): Joan Ray / [.116?] 4.5 S.F.
    Half length portrait of Warren seated behind desk.
    Portraits; Warren, Earl, -- 1891-1974 -- Portraits
  - Aspinwall California Railway, [ca. 1852]; Nahl, H.W. Arthur; BANC PIC 1971.003--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 54.9 x 75.3 cm. Handwritten (verso, UL): H. A. A. / 29031. UCB label (verso): 71-10-00468. Auction labels on verso.
    The Panama railroad was built across the Isthmus of Panama by William Henry Aspinwall from 1850-52. The town of Aspinwall was established in 1852 and served as its western terminus when the railroad was finished. The railroad carried many miners to California during the gold rush and was the fastest shipping route between New York and San Francisco before transcontinental railroad was completed in 1869.
    View of a train engine and car crossing a body of water in Aspinwall (later renamed Colon) Panama. The turnaround is visible in the foreground and a church with a classical façade stands on a hill with the town beyond.
    Oil paintings; Panama Railroad Co. -- Pictorial works; Railroads -- Panama -- Pictorial works; Col/ac\on (Panama) -- Pictorial works